A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 2, Accession 2 FA1184
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Conferences, Seminars, Workshops and Dialogues, 1984-2006; 5
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue (Postponed): Hong Kong Planning, 1995 November 30 - December 10 (Box 17, Folder 146)
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue (Postponed): Scholar Orientation Program (SOP) Reunion Planning, 1995 November 30 - December 10 (Box 17, Folder 147)
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue: Background and Planning, 1996 June 22-30 (Box 17, Folder 148)
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue: Correspondence, 1996 June 22-30 (Box 17, Folder 149)
    Includes Follow-Up correspondence.
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue: Correspondence, 1996 June 22-30 (Box 17, Folder 149A)
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue: Finances and Reporting, 1996 June 22-30 (Box 17, Folder 150)
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue: Participants, 1996 June 22-30 (Box 17, Folder 151)
  - Eighth United States - China Dialogue: Notes and Transcripts, 1996 June 22-30 (Box 17, Folder 152-153)
    Includes notes by Jan Berris and typed transcripts of taped discussions.
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Correspondence and Planning, 1997 December 12-15 (Box 17, Folder 154)
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Correspondence and Planning, 1997 December 12-15 (Box 18, Folder 155)
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Namelists, Bios, and Invites, 1997 December 12-15 (Box 18, Folder 156)
    Chinese and American participants. Includes brochure.
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Namelists, Bios, and Invites, 1997 December 12-15; FA1184:032; Digital Media: Floppy Disk
    Disk labeled "Ninth U.S.-China Dialogue Invites, Chinese Participant Address list."
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Background Reading, 1997 December 12-15 (Box 18, Folder 157)
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Notes on Discussions and Meetings, 1997 December 12-15 (Box 18, Folder 158)
    Notes on Dialogue discussions and other meetings. The manuscript "Notes from Dialogue" was originally filed with the 1996 Dialogue, but internal evidence links it to the 1997 meetings.
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Chinese Delegation Meetings and Trip, 1997 December 10-21 (Box 18, Folder 159)
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Thank Yous and Follow-Up, 1997 December 12-15 (Box 18, Folder 160)
  - Ninth United States - China Dialogue: Thank Yous and Follow-Up, 1997 December 12-15; FA1184:005; Still Images: 2 4x6 color prints (Box 42, Folder 160)
    Two photos of Dialogue participants (includes Mei Zhaorong, Barber Conable, Michel Oksenberg, and unidentifed man).
  - United States - China Dialogues: Reports, 1985-1997 (Box 18, Folder 161)
    Compilation of individual Dialogue reports.
  - Tenth United States - China Dialogue (Postponed): Background and Planning, 1999 May 28 - June 9 (Box 18, Folder 162)
  - Tenth United States - China Dialogue (Postponed): Namelists and Bios, 1999 May 28 - June 9 (Box 19, Folder 163)
    Includes Bios of Chinese participants (in January 2000 dialogue).
  - United States - China Dialogue (Mini Dialogue), 1999 June 25-29 (Box 19, Folder 164)
  - Tenth United States - China Dialogue: Background and Planning, 2000 January 8-18 (Box 19, Folder 165-167)
    Beijing. Includes finances and post-trip accounting.
  - Tenth United States - China Dialogue: American Participants, 2000 January 8-18 (Box 19, Folder 168)
  - Tenth United States - China Dialogue: Guizhou Trip, 2000 January 8-18 (Box 19, Folder 169)
  - Tenth United States - China Dialogue: Notes, Thank Yous, and Follow-Up, 2000 January 8-18 (Box 19, Folder 170)
  - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue: Background and Planning, 2002 June 14-16 (Box 19, Folder 171)
  - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue: Participants, 2002 June 14-16 (Box 19, Folder 172)
  - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue: Chinese Delegation Meetings and Trip, 2002 June 13-23 (Box 20, Folder 173)
  - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue: Report, Notes, and Follow-Up, 2002 June 14-16 (Box 20, Folder 174)
  - United States - China Dialogue (Cancelled), 2004 September 9-10 (Box 20, Folder 175)
    Brewster, NY.
  - U.S. - China (Volcker - Henry Luce; U.S. - China X2 (Rock - St(illegible)), undated; FA1184:028 - FA1184:029; Audio: 2 unidentified cassette tapes.
    Cassette tape labeled "U.S. China" (Volcker - Henry Luce) and "U.S. China X2" (Rock - St(illegible)). The tapes presumably form a pair documenting a single event.
- Programs, Projects, and Proposals, 1966-1973, 2002-2008; 8
  The Programs, Projects, and Proposals series in RG 2 contains records of the NCUSCR's University Field Staff program, 1966-1973, which engaged graduate students and faculty in organizing workshops and other educational outreach programs on China on campus and in their surrounding communities.
  The series also includes the records of the U. S. – China Labor Law Cooperation Project, 2002-2007, a five-year project to improve labor laws in China, which the National Committee, together with the Asia Foundation and Worldwide Strategies, Inc., conducted under contract from the U. S. Department of Labor. National Committee involvement focused on drafting the Labor Contract Law and Regulations on Labor and Social Security Inspection. The Committee organized workshops in China, as well as U. S. study tours and internships for Chinese legislative and labor officials, and then developed a curriculum and training program for Chinese labor inspectors.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Agreement, 2003 November (Box 20, Folder 176)
    U. S. Department of Labor project document for technical cooperation with China.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Proposal to the U. S. Department of Labor, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 177)
    Submission to the China Labor Rule of Law Program, jointly with Worldwide Strategies Inc. and the Asia Foundation.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Management Documents, 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 178)
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Performance Monitoring Plan, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 179)
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Management Team and Project Advisory Committee Meetings, 2004-2005 (Box 20, Folder 180)
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Budgets, 2003-2005 (Box 21, Folder 181-182)
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Contacts and Specialists, 2004-2005 (Box 21, Folder 183)
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Management Procedures and Guidelines (U.S. Department of Labor), 2003 (Box 21, Folder 184)
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Project Correspondence and Planning, 2002-2007 (Box 21, Folder 185)
    Correspondence, memos, and notes pertaining to project planning and programs.
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Project Correspondence and Planning, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 186)
    Correspondence, planning, and reports. File may have been maintained by Ling Li.
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Project Correspondence and Planning, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 187)
  - U.S.- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Reports, 2004-2007 (Box 21, Folder 188)
    Mainly Technical Progress Reports to the U.S. Department of Labor, Office of Foreign Relations. Also includees report on May 2004 Labor Inspection Regulations Workshop in Qingdao.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Final Desk Audit, 2007 November (Box 22, Folder 189)
    Bureau of International Labor Affairs, U.S. Department of Labor.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Final Report 2002-2007 (Box 22, Folder 190)
    Published report on project.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Law Background Reading: General, 1996-2008 (Box 22, Folder 191-192)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Law Background Reading: Mary Gallagher, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 193)
    Papers and articles.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Law Background Reading: Labor Relations, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 194)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Law Background Reading: Labor Standards, 2001-2005 (Box 22, Folder 195)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Law Background Reading: Overtime Rule, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 196)
    Original folder labeled, "Overtime Rule, John Fraser." Case study of Impactt Ltd. project to reduce overtime in China.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Law Background Reading: Federal Regulations, 1993-2004 (Box 22, Folder 197)
    U. S. Department of Labor publications.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Law in China: Other Programs, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 198)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Regulations Workshop: General, 2004 May 17-19 (Box 23, Folder 199)
    Workshop on Labor And Social Security Inspections (Qingdao). Program book, trip report, budget.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Regulations Workshop: Potential Team Members, 2004 May 17-19 (Box 23, Folder 200)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Regulations Workshop: Draft Regulations and Team Comments, 2004 May 17-19 (Box 23, Folder 201)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Senior Labor Inspectors Delegation (from China), 2004 December 4-17 (Box 23, Folder 202)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Strengthening the Work of Chinese Legal Aid Centers Internships (Participants) (from China), 2005 February 27 - April 2 (Box 23, Folder 203)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Contract Law Seminar (in China), 2005 June 4-9 (Box 23, Folder 204)
    Drafting workshop no. 1. Background and Drafts.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Contract Law Study Delegation (from China), 2005 July 9-22 (Box 23, Folder 205-207)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Legislative Training Project Internships (from China): Briefing Book and Program Materials, 2005 October 8 - November 11 (Box 24, Folder 208-210)
    Briefing book and supplementary material. Also includes brochure and report on the Senior Labor Inspectors Delegation, December 2004.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Legislative Training Project Internships (from China): Planning Correspondence, 2005 October 8 - November 11 (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Contract Law Study Delegation and Draft Revision Workshop, 2005 July - 2006 December (Box 24, Folder 212)
    Materials removed from Binder. Labor Contract Law Study Delegation Study Tour of the U.S., 2005 July 9-22; Workshop on Revision of the Draft Labor Contract Law, Kunming, 2006 December 4-6.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Contract Law Workshop (Kunming), 2006 December 4-6 (Box 24, Folder 213)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Contract Law Workshop (Kunming), 2006 December; FA1184:006; Still Image: Laminated 7 x 14 color print (group photo). (Box 42, Folder 213)
    Group photo of participants in Labor Contract Law workshop and/or other December Labor Law programs.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Contract Law Workshop (Kunming) (Visa and Travel Arrangements), 2006 December 4-6 (Box 25, Folder 214)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Workshop on Labor Inspection (Shanghai), 2007 May 17-18 (Box 25, Folder 215)
    Program material.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Workshop on Labor Inspection (Shanghai), 2007 May 17-18; FA1184:007; Still Image: 8 x 12 color print (group photo) (Box 42, Folder 215)
    Group photo
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Curriculum Development and Training, 2005-2007 (Box 25, Folder 216-217)
    Project notebook for Training of Trainers sessions, containing planning correspondence and administrative and background materials. Draft copy of Labor Inspector Training Outline, plus Visa and Travel information, added to this file in processing.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Curriculum Development and Training, 2007 July 30 - August 10; FA1184:008; Still Image: 7.5 x 10 color print (group photo) (Box 42, Folder 216)
    Group photo of Training of Trainers session participants.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Curriculum Development and Training, 2007 August 10; FA1184:009; Still Image: 8 x 12 color print (group photo) (Box 42, Folder 216)
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection in China, Train-the-Trainers Manual, 2007 July (Box 25, Folder 218-219)
    June 2007 draft Manual for Training of Trainers sessions, July 30 - August 10, 2007, and project background and planning book.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Program Evaluation Forms, 2004 December - 2005 July (Box 25, Folder 220)
    Evaluation forms from Labor Inspectors Visit, December 2004; Labor Contract Law Drafting Workshop, June 2005; and Study/Training Program, (July 2005?).
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Workshop Evaluation Forms, 2006 December - 2007 May (Box 26, Folder 221)
    Evaluation forms from Labor Law Contract Workshop and Workshop on Labor Inspection.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Workshop Evaluation Forms, 2007 July 30 - August 10 (Box 26, Folder 222)
    Labor Inspection Training of Trainer Sessions.
  - Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), Compliance Assistance: Youth 2 Work Specialty Series, 2003 October 3; FA1184:038; Digital Media: 1 CD
    Packaged CD presentation.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Senior Labor Inspectors Delegation (Meetings - Washington, DC): (U.S. Department of Labor) Power Point Presentations, 2004 December 6-8; FA1184:039; Digital Media - 1 compact disc
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Senior Labor Inspectors Delegation (Meetings - San Francisco): U. S. Department of Labor, Employment Standards Administration, Wage and Hour Division, George Friday Western Regional Administrator, 2004 December 13-14; FA1184:040; Digital Media - 1 compact disc
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Workshop on Labor Inspection (Shanghai) and Training of Trainers, (2007 May - August?); FA1184:033; Digital Media: 1 DVD.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection, Training of Trainers, Flash, 2007; FA1184:034; Digital Media: 1 CD.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Essentials for Protecting your Labor Rights, Undated; FA1184:035; Digital Media: 1 CD
    Packaged CD presentation (same cover design as sets of Labor Inspection Training of Trainers discs.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Workshop on Labor Inspection (Shanghai), 2007 May 17-18; FA1184:036; Digital Media: 1 CD
  - Unlabeled DVD, FA1184:037; Digital Media: 1 DVD.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Training of Trainers (Disks 7-12), 2007 July 30 - August 10; FA1184:043; Digital Media (6 DVDs)
    Packaged set of presentations.
  - U.S. - China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Training of Trainers (Disks 13-18), 2007 July 30 - August 10; FA1184:044; Digital Media (6 DVDs)
  - U.S- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: Labor Inspection Training of Trainers, Beijing. Clip, 2007 August; FA1184:041; Digital Media: 1 DVD
    Also labeled, NCUSCR.dv
  - U.S- China Labor Law Cooperation Project: NCUSCR 10.1 presentation, Training of Trainers Training Video, Beijing, 2008 January 22; FA1184:042; Digital Media: 1 DVD
  - University Field Staff Program: General, 1967-1972 (Box 26, Folder 223-224)
  - University Field Staff Program: Arne de Keijzer, Coordinator, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 225)
  - University Field Staff Program: Colorado Field Staff, 1970-1973 (Box 26, Folder 226)
  - University Field Staff Program: Colorado Field Staff - Trade Conference, 1974 May 23 (Box 26, Folder 227)
  - University Field Staff Program: Columbia Field Staff, 1967-1972 (Box 26, Folder 228-229)
  - University Field Staff Program: Florida State University Field Staff, 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 230)
  - University Field Staff Program: Florida State University Field Staff, 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 230A)
  - University Field Staff Program: Harvard Field Staff, 1966-1972 (Box 27, Folder 231-232)
  - University Field Staff Program: Harvard Field Staff (Reports), 1966-1969 (Box 27, Folder 233)
  - University Field Staff Program: Hawaii Field Staff, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 234)
  - University Field Staff Program: Southern Illinois University Field Staff, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 235)
  - University Field Staff Program: Southern Illinois University Field Staff, 1972-1973; FA1184:010; Still Image: 1 Black and White 6.75 x 10 print. (Box 42, Folder 235)
    Group photo of attendees at formal dinner. Occasion not identified, but appears to be "Symposium on Sin-American D‚tente," sponsored by Asian Studies Program, Southern Illinois University, Edwardsville, and held in Bermuda, June 9-10, 1973. Photograph by Glenn T. Correia.
  - University Field Staff Program: University of Kansas, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 236)
  - University Field Staff Program: Michigan Field Staff, 1967-1969 (Box 27, Folder 237-240)
  - University Field Staff Program: Michigan Field Staff, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 241-244)
  - University Field Staff Program: Princeton Field Staff, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 245)
  - University Field Staff Program: Seattle Field Staff, 1969-1972 (Box 28, Folder 246-247)
    University of Washington.
  - University Field Staff Program: Seton Hall Field Staff, 1970-1973 (Box 28, Folder 248)
  - University Field Staff Program: Southern California Field Staff, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 249-250)
    UCLA
  - University Field Staff Program: Stanford Field Staff, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 251)
  - University Field Staff Program: Virginia Field Staff, 1970-1973 (Box 29, Folder 252-253)
  - University Field Staff Program: Virginia Field Staff, 1972-1973; FA1184:053; Oversize: 11.75 x 17.5 Broadside (Box 43)
    Poster announcement for Chinese Culture Week, March 5-10, (1973)